<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Starting on Airspace for Hugo</title>
    <link>https://icareerclimber.github.io/categories/starting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Starting on Airspace for Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://icareerclimber.github.io/categories/starting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://icareerclimber.github.io/howitworks/1-getting-the-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://icareerclimber.github.io/howitworks/1-getting-the-data/</guid>
      <description>[1] Data Collection Using Python Selenium and Beautiful Soup libraries to build web scraping tools, our team collected from the web over 600k unique resumes and 1.1 million salary records representing over 5500 cities across 20 years.
Link to Code

[2] Data Transformation Data ingestion pipelines were created to standardize the data inputs from various sources.

Jobs Title Job titles vary widely from resume to resume, so we created a heuristic to process each job title into a standard format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification Models</title>
      <link>https://icareerclimber.github.io/howitworks/2-classification-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://icareerclimber.github.io/howitworks/2-classification-models/</guid>
      <description>[1] Document Similarity We provide career recommendations in a ranked order based on the similarity of a job seeker&amp;rsquo;s current/past job experiences. Our model is powered by resume information all across the US.
This product is a proof of concept and contains a small subset of possible jobs. Our model contains 114 unique job titles. The list of job titles is derived from the availability of salary information. We selected all jobs that contained at least 100 salary records in the past 5 years and 500 resume job summaries in the past 10 years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>